pearl.com 2017-12-26

# Privacy & Security | JustAnswer

Updated: March 23, 2017

Inherent to transacting on the Internet is the collection of some personal information. JustAnswer LLC ("JustAnswer") is committed to protecting your personal information and privacy. This Privacy Statement applies exclusively to the Site [www.JustAnswer.com](http://www.justanswer.com/), which includes the Site ww2.justanswer.com and the Site [http://my.justanswer.com](http://my.justanswer.com/), which is owned and operated by JustAnswer (collectively, "Sites"). This policy describes the personal information we collect from you and how we use and secure it. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. "Personal Information" ("PII or Personally Identiable Information") defines information such as name and email that can identify an individual.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

For queries and concerns pertaining to the Site, click [HERE](http://ww2.justanswer.com/help) to contact us.

**Because your privacy is important to us, JustAnswer® operates by the following principles.**

Capitalized terms not defined in this Agreement will have the meanings set forth in the Terms of Service.

**Principle 1: Information We Collect**

If you choose to provide us with your PII, you are agreeing to the processing and storage of your information in the United States and countries outside of the United States which may have data protection laws that differ from laws in your country.

JustAnswer generally explicitly asks when it needs PII. To help facilitate the question and response process, and the payment of Experts via PayPal™, JustAnswer requires basic data such as email address. To obtain payments from Customers, JustAnswer asks for either credit card information or PayPal™ email address, at the Customer's election. Expert applicants and/or referral participants may be asked for additional information, such as full names, addresses, telephone numbers, professional license and certification information, and payment-related information. Experts who win prizes on the site may be required to provide shipment addresses. If you choose to use our referral program to recommend potential Experts to the site, to tell a friend or others about JustAnswer, or send a copy of a question and answer sequence to a friend, you may need to provide your and their email addresses (and possibly their and your names). We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site.  JustAnswer stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at by clicking to request that we remove this information from our database. If you choose to have JustAnswer notify you of responses to your questions via text message, you will be asked for your cellular phone number and cellular phone company. Other PII may be requested in certain circumstances or collected on a voluntary basis such as on users' profile or signature pages. If you are a referral participant and elect to receive payments via check, we will receive all information necessary to distribute a check to you, such as your name and mailing address.

As explained in the JustAnswer Terms of Service, _information provided by you in the content of your questions_ , answers, and other posts on the Site, in Expert profiles describing your experiences and qualifications, and in signatures attached to postings on the Site ("Posts") _is not private or confidential_. This is an Internet-based forum(akin to a modern version of a radio call-in program) and information submitted in Posts may be read, collected, and used by others, and JustAnswer is not responsible for it.  For example, search engines may index your questions, answers, and other Posts to allow them to _appear in search engine results_ ( _e.g._ if someone does a search on google.com, your questions, answers, and other Posts on JustAnswer.com that relate to the search may appear in the google.com search results list). Protect your anonymity by not including your real name or any PII in your questions, answers, and other Posts on the Site.

In some cases, JustAnswer supplements portions of the PII you provide with data sent to us from your web browser including (depending on its settings) your IP address, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data ("Usage Statistics"). JustAnswer may also supplement your user profile with a phone number if you call our customer service center and the customer service agent who answers your call is able to identify your phone number. This allows customer service agents to better help you by allowing them to match your phone number when you next call to your user profile.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

Technologies such as: cookies and similar technologies are used by JustAnswer and our partners such as our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers including customer service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.

JustAnswer is intended for adult use only. In addition, it does not knowingly solicit or collect PII from persons under 13 years old. We may delete from the site PII, as well as Posts and other information, from users we believe are under the age of 18.

**Principle 2: Use of Your Information**

JustAnswer® may use, share, transfer, or disclose your PII and/or Usage Statistics, itself or in conjunction with third parties, for payment processing, fraud prevention, customer service, demographic studies, to tailor JustAnswer's content and services to its users' needs, and to serve advertisements.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [HERE](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

JustAnswer posts testimonials on the Site; we obtain permission prior to posting to include the user's name and state of residence, or their initials. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us by clicking [HERE](http://ww2.justanswer.com/contact-us).

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us [HERE](http://ww2.justanswer.com/contact-us).  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

JustAnswer will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. JustAnswer will not otherwise disclose your PII (unless you voluntarily provide it in your Posts), without your consent, unless acting under a good faith belief that such action:

  * in certain situations, JustAnswer may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements;
  * conforms to legal requirements or complies with legal process, such as in complying with a formal request in a court order, subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings or judicial proceeding;
  * serves to protect or defend the rights, property, or safety of JustAnswer, its users, or others; or
  * enforces the JustAnswer Terms of Service or related Agreements.

We may provide your personally identifiable information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as payment processing, sending marketing communications or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We may also share your personal information with other companies from whom you request to receive a specific product or service so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us HERE.

JustAnswer LLC may share your PII with any parent company, subsidiaries, joint venturers, or other companies under common control, in which event it will require that such companies follow this Policy with respect to your PII, unless you are provided with prior written notice. 

If JustAnswer is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

**Principle 3: Correspondence Sent to You**

JustAnswer® will not send you any unsolicited information, including e-mail, except:

(i) Users will receive JustAnswer registration emails when they register, Expert applicants will receive JustAnswer communications relating to their applications, Experts may receive notifications of questions asked in the categories in which they are admitted, and all users will receive updates and notices about questions they are asking or answering, other Posts, their accounts, and new features and policies; these communications are considered part and parcel of your service and, except for the daily digests, you cannot opt out of them;

(ii) Periodically, JustAnswer may contact you about new services, special offers, promotions and third-party / affiliate offers, and will include in any such emails an opt-out link by which you can opt out of receiving such emails; and

(iii) Our customer service and other departments may contact users and referral participants in order to ensure your satisfaction with JustAnswer and/or to ask how we can improve.

**Principle 4: Updating and Deleting PII**

Upon request, JustAnswer will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If at any time you would like to update your PII, please log into your account and access your Edit Profile page. If at any time you would like your PII to be removed from our Site and/or database, or believe that JustAnswer® has not adhered to these privacy principles, please notify us by email by clicking [HERE](http://www.justanswer.com/help/contact.aspx). We will respond to your request within ten business days. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete your PII and/or promptly detect and remedy any problems.

**Principle 5: Links to Third-Party Sites and Use of Third Party Tools**

To the extent that links to other Web sites are contained in Posts on the JustAnswer® site, please note that they are not operated or controlled by JustAnswer and JustAnswer is not responsible for the privacy practices, security, or content of these third-party sites.

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

If a user decides to take advantage of third-party tools, including but not limited to, Remote Desktop applications, such user agrees that any third-party software acquired, installed or used during the Remote Desktop session will be licensed by the user and such user must accept any terms of use of such third-party tool, including any third-party privacy policy.  JustAnswer is not responsible for any use or misuse of such third-party tool.

**Principle 6: Security and Data Retention**

JustAnswer® follows generally accepted standards and uses multiple security procedures and practices to protect from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification and disclosure the PII requested from users.

All PII is password protected. All passwords use 160 bit encryption.

JustAnswer uses 128-bit secure socket layer (SSL) technology and digital certificates to encrypt and authenticate transactions (credit card and other payments). SSL creates a secured connection between our web servers and your browser, which protects against unauthorized access to transmitted data and supports data being sent only to intended recipients.

Our database logs important changes so that unauthorized transactions can be quickly reversed.

Our main servers are locked and hosted by a leading provider of Internet access to enterprises with mission-critical Internet application requirements. Access to the host environment is highly secure. Biometric scanning, 24/7 onsite staff monitoring, and other safeguards are utilized. In addition, back-up servers that are stripped of email addresses, passwords, and credit card information are located in an office that is locked outside of normal business hours.

Despite these security procedures and practices, as is the case with all computer networks connected to the Internet, JustAnswer cannot guarantee the security of your PII or any other information provided over the Internet and will not be responsible for breaches of security.

We retain your account information and the information provided by you in the form of Posts indefinitely until such time that we determine it has no further commercial significance, at which time we may delete and/or aggregate and store it in aggregate form indefinitely. We may also retain and use this information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Principle 7: Updates to This Policy**

By visiting JustAnswer®, you are accepting this policy as it may be amended from time to time. Please check the date of this Policy each time you visit to ensure that you are aware of the most current version. If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy, please do not use this site.

JustAnswer reserves the right to update this policy at any time without prior notice. Material updates will take effect 30 days after initial posting on this site, to which we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by clicking HERE or mail us at 38 Keyes Avenue, Suite 150, San Francisco, CA 94129.
